{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following is/are not a gram-positive bacteria?", "opta": "Streptococci", "optb": "Pseudomonas", "optc": "Mycobacteria", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gram-positive bacteria, responsible for food poisoning, is/are", "opta": "Mycoplasmas", "optb": "Pseudomonas", "optc": "Clostridia", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The gram-positive bacteria lack __________ structure/component?", "opta": "outer membrane", "optb": "murein", "optc": "teichoic acid", "optd": "plasma membrane", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gram-positive bacteria causes pharyngitis (sore throat)?", "opta": "Neisseria", "optb": "Streptococcus", "optc": "Staphylococcus", "optd": "Mycobacterium", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gram-negative bacteria is/are not aerobic?", "opta": "Pseudomonas", "optb": "Neisseria", "optc": "Escherichia", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzyme, which hydrolyses the murein is", "opta": "perxoidase", "optb": "tannase", "optc": "lysozyme", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacterial spoilage is identified by which of the following morphological characteristics?", "opta": "Encapsulation", "optb": "Endospores", "optc": "Cell aggregation", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacteria are", "opta": "saprophytic", "optb": "symbiotic", "optc": "hyper parasitic", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gram-negative bacteria, responsible for food poisoning, is/are", "opta": "Salmonella", "optb": "Pseudomonas", "optc": "Clostridia", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coliform bacteria on fermentation of carbohydrates yields", "opta": "lactic acid", "optb": "acetic acid", "optc": "formic acid", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gram-negative bacterium is/are", "opta": "Escherichia", "optb": "Clostridia", "optc": "Staphylococci", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thermus thermopiles is a", "opta": "gram negative eubacteria", "optb": "gram positive eubacteria", "optc": "gram negative archebacteria", "optd": "gram positive archebacteria", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a gram-positive bacteria?", "opta": "Lactobacillus", "optb": "Staphylococci", "optc": "Streptococci", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}